而家夠法定人數，就邀請啊律師會嘅代表入嚟，正式啊宣佈會議開始。
係你件事啊！
我哋作條標啦，好嘛？
係今日第一條標係咪？係呢個嚇。
醬。
呢個。
呀。
幾個commercial notice佢唔係一齊合併咧，好唔好啊？合併就佢哋自己視意邊個。
多謝，Mr.
McKenzie, Miss McKenzie and Mr. Cohen and all others representative, thank you for coming. It's just a brief meeting to go through some of the bylaws and some of the queries that our legal adviser in this committee has raised last time. So for the sake
cost efficiency. I decide to combine the discussion together, and we have five pilots.
所以，我們會想開始講講《 commencement notice》 of the bylaws。
所以，啊。
Who will speak first of?
我。
Perhaps you let us know exactly what's causing concern because I thought we had a previous time we came before you, we went through and explained everything, all the changes. I think the issue which is perhaps causing some concern is why the one year to come into effect. Is that the gist of it all? So let me explain. Let me explain. I'll leave legal.
Advisor in particular has raised the concern that why it takes so long. Let me explain that. So you just briefly tell us why. First of all, I think you have to realise we have now 8,000 solicitors.
The changes that we put forward are substantial changes, and it's very, very important that the profession has the proper time to able to really understand what they have to do.
所以，你 need that time for let's say the following reasons. First of all, we had to put forward a new manual.
To be honest, it takes time to draft a manual, to get it circulated, to get comments back, and we've only just had comments back from the accountants to have it amend circulate the manual.
The next time is that all members of a law society say, well, we need proper courses set up. So we set up a whole lot of sort of special courses, remedial, etc. lectures, and that takes time to get all those lectures together. So everyone is fully au fait in respect of all of those lectures as well.
系統、電腦系統， to be very frank and very honest, these changes for the large firms are easy. But if you are just a sole proprietor, and if you look at the demographics of the members of a law society, 70% or 80% are either sole practitioners or two partners. It's quite strange actually. Hong Kong, if you
Look at the legal profession in the world. Hong Kong is a complete opposite to anyone else. The number of large firms are not very—you know—they're the big city firms, the American firms. Even my small firm with 20 members is up at size 35 or 40.
出於數量六七百間律師行，所以這些小律師行需要幫助。他們需要有機會去上講座，需要被問問題。在最後一天，律師行在他們的智慧下，考慮到所有後果，他們覺得這是正確的時間去做。現在，是的，它可以更快完成。
我 got a little bit personally putting on my examiner's hat. I wanted to examine on this in the overseas lawyers qualifying exam, but my knuckles were firmly wrapped, saying I can't because everyone's got to be taught about it as well. So, you know, overall, if you look at it as a whole, and one other thing, I recollect when the companies ordinance came into place, if you remember, there was a
long year period to give people, they promulgated it and then they had a commencement period about a year, so everyone got up to date. So in a nutshell, yeah.
Not every some people want it quicker, but I think in the end of the day.
The wisdom of the Law Society Council decided that we wanted to do this. So that's it in a nutshell. Prepare to answer any questions. Anything else? And also, accounting firms of law firms are one year. So
You know, asking them to change suddenly affects their accounting year, and so that goes in within what Mr. Cohen said about systems. End of year, some people at March, some people at December. So it just gives everyone the opportunity to get it together. Okay. Okay. Let our member ask their questions. So the first one is Mr. Dennis Kwok.
係。
The reason why we we ask you to come is is also for for part of the record, because if if anyone wishes to question later on why it took four years etc etc, we know you have good answers to those questions. But we just want to formally put it on record. But you raised a very good point just now, which is also part of my concern.
regarding foreign law firms, because part of the commencement notice covers the foreign lawyers' practice. And you raise a very good point as to why foreign law firms should not be subject to the same requirement. I understand that they are subject to the same requirement.
But why foreign lawyers OLQE exams, not solicitor account rules, is not a subject which OLQE should be well? Let me answer that question. It is a subject, and I'm the examiner for that, and the exam is.
On Thursday, what I said here is because the principles are that you only examine on the law in force on the 31st of August.
Exams are every November. Now, if you're a lecturer at universities and you've got to teach, it really can be quite awkward. So, you look at the 31st of August. What's in force at the 31st of August is examined on, even with cases as well. So, everyone who's sitting the overseas lawyers qualifying exam sits accounts and professional conduct.
你 gotta pass both parts as well.
I would have liked to have examined these new rules on that basis, but in the end of the day, the committee's took the view would not be fair because it technically had not come into commencement date or enforce. That is my point. I think I think they should be tested in the court. Well, it will be tested. I mean, it.
The accounts rules are there. It's the old rules that are tested. The new rule will not come into place until July. So when I set the paper for next year's accounts rules, of course it will be all tested. So actually, it's a matter of time. So it will be tested. It will be tested. It will certainly will be tested in no uncertain terms. I mean.
You know, but also you do have to realise this. I mean, to be also to be very frank and honest, if you look at these amendment rules, they are in essence a sort of codification of putting everything together. Yes, there are four or five substantial changes which have to be dealt with: splitting of checks and various sort of ways in treating clients' money, but
Courses are in place, so people who are going to be examined on it will be examined on it, but not for this year's. They're taking the law in force on the 31st of August. It's the same with every single subject. So, for example, if you have a quarter-final appeal decision that is handed down between the 31st of August and when they sit the exams, which are all this week, they're not examined.
被examined as to the law in place on the 31st. The reason for that is that courses are put in place, and the examiners and everyone says, "Well, how can you do that?" But always a clever student always writes something in the exam paper to get an extra mark.
Okay. And also, if the foreign lawyer in question comes from a jurisdiction that has very different accounts, for say,
一個jurisdiction we're not familiar with. Would you deal with those cases differently, or when when when those law firms are practising in Hong Kong with the Law Society have an enhanced programme looking at these law firms and the way they practise? Well, Mr. Cohen. Well, if they're meant to be very honest, you have to comply with the council rules. They cannot.
律師律所，The foreign law firm if established here in Hong Kong must comply with the relevant rules attributable to practising in Hong Kong. So they are under the complete auspices of a law society, and if they are in breach of any of the rules, how they hold clients' money, they will be for the high jump. And also the new guide to professional conduct in
obligates foreign lawyers practising in foreign law firms with complying with the rules, and they.
Chapter one also deals with conflict of issues, and in fact, the new guide to professional conduct incorporates the International Bar Association rules. And so, where there is a conflict between their own jurisdiction ethical rules and the Hong Kong ethical rules, then you look at the International Bar Association principles and how those conflicts are to be resolved. Okay.
Okay, so it's a matter of fairness. Well, I'll tell you what, you know, time and time again, I think we actually would be hard on the foreign lawyers now to make sure they do comply. We do know they have to, and I and you know they're all aware of this rules and they will be aware of it all. And they, you know, they don't comply with it, they have a big problem. Yeah, maybe they can.
be trained again to update themselves in the course. Well, every lawyer for those who have already missed this, every lawyer should be updating themselves every day. Okay. The reason why I raise that is because I want to ensure there's a level playing field between foreign lawyers and the Hong Kong lawyers, so that everyone competes on the same level playing field.
The solicitor rules have been made into the risk management programme, and therefore taking the solicitor council rules is a risk management issue. Considered. And foreign lawyers and lawyers are being trained on that. Okay. Okay. Any more questions? Yes, Felix. So the major explanations.
From the law society on why it took a bit long to to get it ready, is you have to explain everything, to do seminars to for for all your members. So right now, I believe that all your members are very clear about the procedure and everything, and.
我 also notice that you you need to take some time to engage with the Hong Kong MA and also.
The Hong Kong Association. Yeah, yeah, for the banking. Yeah, the bank and the monetary authority. So everything is set up and ready to go. Yeah, absolutely. Because I mean, one area which is a good thing is that we've had problems in the past with law firms who the law society had to intervene in solicitors go rogue, and unfortunately it happens. Some of those solicitors who go rogue.
Had accounts, clients' accounts offshore, and that was really great problems in trying to recover money on behalf of the clients. So we stopped all of that. You got to have your accounts in Hong Kong, but you can apply for waivers, and we got to get this all set up as well. So that's one area where it needs a bit of time to make sure everyone is fully aware as to that fact. But I believe that you.
我哋有過 Overseas claims，係啊。
Will there be involved in overseas bank account? No, you got to have your accounts. We're Hong Kong law firms. Everything has to be in Hong Kong. Absolutely. The principle is that you cannot.
Manage a Hong Kong law firm and regulate a Hong Kong law firm which has accounts overseas because you have no power overseas, and therefore, in order to ensure that the public is protected, all accounts must be in Hong Kong so that the law side. So, what sort? Sorry about that. What sort of thing you particularly have to be connected with the?
香港 Monetary Monetary Authority。
It is to advise. I don't think it's too much for the monetary authority. To be very frank, it's advising law firms who have accounts in Shanghai, in China, in London as well. They can't do that anymore. They need to, you know, get their money back into Hong Kong. If their clients' money offshore, their clients' money must be in Hong Kong. To protect the clients. Yeah.
Just purely to protect the other issues. Also, monetary authority would be in relation to banks because solicitor's client accounts must have the word 'client account' written on the on the checkbooks and the bank statements. And so, we want to make sure that banks understand the need for solicitor's client account checkbooks and statements to have the words.
Client account written on them, and so all banks must understand that. We can only do that. Few banks didn't understand that. Few banks, most banks would let you put the word client account, but believe it or not, one or two were being a bit saying, "Well, we don't." But now they all do. So we're making sure that everybody is in tune with that. Yeah. Okay, Felix. Any more? If not, I think we're.
We're ready to pass all this and to endorse it and.
just two week did, okay.
Okay. Do I need to go through it?
Bill by Bill, no need, yeah, okay. So I think we would pass them on one lot. And thank you for coming because you know it's another word now. So you can just come and so we we need to record it.
Always a pleasure to come here. So, so let us repeat again. I think the time for the amendment date has been extended to the 2 December 2015.
Okay. No, second December. No, it's in July. July. July. July.
July two hundred one six.
That's what it should be.
咪收緊咗咯。
send it to我。
Yes, it says two one six.
First July two zero. Yeah, we're not talking about the commencement date. We're talking about the procedure at the legislative. So that the discussion, actually, we have extended it to second December, and we will pass it to the House Committee.
In the house committee, we read it and and everything is done. So thank you for that. Thank you for coming. Okay, thank you very much. Thank you. Thank you all.